<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>a_coding_story</title><description>Learning to code at Makers Academy</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.6</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 21:05:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>It's the start of something new...</title><description>&lt;p&gt;...for Lucy. That's me. And this is my story on how I'm learning to be a coder...with the help of Makers Academy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="whydoiwanttocode"&gt;Why do I want to code?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having worked in the marketing and communications area for over a decade, I was always in awe of the brilliant technicians&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/welcome-to-ghost/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">416e0067-d8e5-462a-8903-de27191f14b9</guid><category>Getting Started</category><dc:creator>Lucy Fang</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 18:33:40 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;...for Lucy. That's me. And this is my story on how I'm learning to be a coder...with the help of Makers Academy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="whydoiwanttocode"&gt;Why do I want to code?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having worked in the marketing and communications area for over a decade, I was always in awe of the brilliant technicians who can create, build, and make amazing websites and applications. While I found managing various projects was a great experience, I never felt completely satisfied with sitting on the bench. I always envied their technical skills and wished "I could do that!". So it was time to stop wishing, wondering and self-doubting, and give myself a chance to learn. I started self-learning online after work and found that I actually enjoyed coming home to code rather than work! That's a sure sign that you actually love what you are learning! I decided that even if I wasn't any good, there would be no regrets and I won't be left wondering what could have been! Besides, "you gotta risk it to get the biscuit". I can't remember who said that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here begins my journey to learn to code with Makers Academy. And why Makers? There's so many ways to learn and you've got to pick the one that's right for you. I looked into all options including learning on my own, online courses or bootcamps like Makers. I chose Makers because of their curriculum, supportive teachers and open learning environment. I also wanted to meet new people, learn from others and have that face-to-face contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="andweek1sofar"&gt;And Week 1 so far ...&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bootcamp at Makers is 12 weeks and there's one month pre-course. The pre-course is important to help prep us for the bootcamp so there's heaps to do. We are given exercises and challenges to do every week and week 1 is all about the command line! I never realised how powerful and useful the command line is! I feel like everything is at my fingertips (pause for a Mr. Burns moment) and that gives me much satisfaction! I will sure be using it a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>